字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
再来两份油甘鱼的
And some hamachi. Two pieces.
什么是假日卷
What is a "holiday roll"?
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
我迟到了 抱歉
I'm late, I know. Sorry.
他们让我工作了一个小时
They kept me at work an extra hour.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好
Okay.
脸怎么了
What's that?
我从自行车上摔下来了
I fell off my bike.
- 就这辆车  - 对
- That thing?  - Yeah.
感觉你从来不骑
Looks like you never rode it.
现在知道原因了吧
And you see why?
你总是不说到底在做什么工作
You've carefully avoided saying what this job is.
和你说过了 我才刚刚入行
I told you, it's entry level.
不过升职很快
But there's a fast track to promotion.
类似于经理一类的
Kind of manager.
类似于麦当劳吗
Kind of McDonald's?
对
Yeah.
我给你带了个礼物
I brought you a present.
其实是乔西给你的礼物
It's from Josie, really.
是她的主意
It was her idea.
你照得还挺帅
You look very handsome.
等孩子出生了 我们再拍一张
We'll go back and take another photo after the birth.
相当于出生前后的对比照
Like a before and after.
乔西有很多装修房子的主意
Josie's full of ideas for decorating.
可她现在才第一次有自己的房子
She never had her own place till now.
你们买房还需要多少钱
How much do you need for the apartment?
我没有借钱的意思
I didn't ask for money.
没事 是我想帮帮你们
No, it was me, hearing voices.
我想请你帮我做担保 不是要借钱
I planned to ask you to provide collateral, not money.
乔西的那些男朋友们
And Josie's boyfriends?
他们有人会搬进去吗
Any of them moving in, too?
没有啊 怎么了
No, why...
该死 刚刚换的衣服
Shit! It was just cleaned.
那女孩什么也干不了
That girl is clearly dysfunctional.
你一点也不了解她
You know nothing about her.
我知道她周围那群人连澡都不洗
Except she was raised in a commune by unwashed idiots.
他们是搞艺术的
An arts collective.
她看上你什么了
Why you? What's she after?
她能看上我什么 我又没钱
What could she be after? I have no money.
我有
I have.
你今天是怎么回事
What's with you today?
我给你三个月房租 但我要先看看房子
I'll give you 3 months' rent. But I look at the place first.
我不想给你压力
I didn't want to pressure you.
你赢了 见好就收吧
You won. Quit while you're ahead.
- 再见  - 再见
- Bye.  - Bye.
把楼上楼下的锁都换了
Change all the locks, upstairs and down.
好的
Okay.
我把钥匙放在信箱里了
I left the key in the mailbox.
多谢了
Thanks a lot.
你看过文森特的房子了吗
You've seen Vincent's apartment?
半年以前他卖大麻还和人打架
6 months ago, he was dealing weed and getting into fights.
你还觉得他是居家好男人
You see him as a family man?
乔西那个臭女人就是个祸害
That bitch Josie is a real menace.
他还看不出来
He just doesn't see it.
关 我们觉得
Kwan, we agreed
这个性高潮的动作太拘谨了
the orgasmic convulsions are way too timid.
好像他们害怕做爱一样
As if they're scared of sex.
动作已经加速了五倍
I upped it 5 times.
看不出来再加速
You can't tell. Push it.
我们能抓重点谈吗
Can we discuss the real issues?
我们只有一次机会打动美国动视
We get one shot at Activision,
但我们的手柄太垃圾
but our controller is so crappy
这个演示片段几乎不能玩
the demo is almost unplayable.
如果玩游戏的人冲屏幕扔手柄的话
What's the point coming up with hyper realistic environments for Stix
给斯迪克斯弄仿真环境还有什么意义
if the player throws the controller through the screen!
库尔特 你跑题了 说故障问题
Kurt, you're off track, focusing on known glitches.
不
No.
真正的问题就在这儿
The real problem is right there.
真正的问题是 你之前做文学出版
The real problem is, your background in publishing and literature
根本没有能力评估游戏的可玩性
is completely inappropriate for evaluating playability.
好吧 也许安娜和我该开另一种公司
Okay, maybe Anna and I should've founded a different sort of company.
可能克隆纳斯的成功
Maybe Kronos was only a hit
全靠的是你的天才想法
thanks to your genius ideas.
可能我们两个就是走了狗屎运
Maybe we're just two bitches who got lucky.
但你要搞清楚
But the fact is,
我才是老板
the boss here is me.
我们已经晚了半年
And we're 6 months behind.
我们的目标很简单 你们都知道
Our goal is simple, as you all know.
玩家手刃妖怪之后
When the player guts an orc,
他得能真正感觉手上有血
he needs to feel the blood on his hands.
粘稠的 热乎的血
Thick, warm blood.
如果可能的话
If at all possible.
我们走
Let's go.
我爱你
I love you.
库尔特恨我 是吗 我多想了吗
Does Kurt hate me or is it just me?
没有 他的确恨你
No, he hates you.
他们都恨你 除了凯文
They all hate you, except Kevin.
即使他用笑来掩饰 他还是很爱你
He really loves you. even if he tries to laugh it off.
你知道的吧
And you knew it, right?
按着这里
Press here.
她知道我想做全面的性病检查吗
She knows I want a full STD panel?
她当然知道
Yes, of course.
如果你担心最近出了问题
If you're worried about a recent exposure,
我可以给你开点阻断药物
I can prescribe a PEP.
不 我在网上看了  副作用太多
No, I looked online. Too many side effects.
我还有工作
I can't miss any work.
听天由命吧
I guess we roll the dice.
喂
Hello?
我晚上刚刚有空
My evening just cleared up.
- 我不行  - 别让我失望
- l can't.  - Make an effort.
我不行 我得
I can't. I have...
我来月经了 感觉不舒服
I have my period. I'm not well.
我带上套子
I'll wear a condom.
感谢你的牺牲精神
I appreciate your sense of sacrifice.
一点血阻挡不了我
A little blood doesn't turn me off.
我不行
No, I can't.
再见
See you.
人渣
Scum!
你和你爸爸
You and your father.
我喜欢你对我做的一切
I love everything you do to me.
我们再来吧
Let's do it again.
下次记得按门铃
Next time, ring the bell.
如果你不想看到不该看的
If you want to avoid being treated to upsetting sights,
那就不会让你看到可怕的东西
Then you won't be treated to gruesome sights.
我还是穿上裤子吧
I'd better put some pants on.
你给了他们多少钱
How much do you pay them?
- 好可悲  - 别可怜我
- It's pitiful!  - Save your pity.
我一点也不觉得丢人
I'm not ashamed.
这是我的生活 我的性生活
It's my life. My sex life.
你真是个小混球 米歇尔
You're a little bitch, Michèle.
我只是说 你有未婚夫 小心点
I'm just saying, with your finances. be careful.
你吃了吗 我做了意面
Did you eat? I made spaghetti.
给我来杯咖啡
I'll take a coffee.
- 不脱了大衣吗  - 我冷
- Not taking your coat off?  - I'm cold.
你们还要继续工作吗
You had more work done?
你能别管了吗
Will you stop going on about that?
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
只是肉毒杆菌而已
Just a little Botox.
是你的事
It's your business.
很好
Very good.
你看上去好吃惊
You seem surprised.
这样好点吧
Better like this?
米歇尔 下一次吧 我得走了
Michèle, some other time, I have to take off.
不 先别走
No. not yet.
我妈和你说了她有艾滋病吗
My mother told you she's HIV-positive?
我警告过拉尔夫你会那么说
I warned Ralf you'd try that one.
见到你很高兴
Nice meeting you.
有个事情 你想好了再回答
One question. Think before you answer.
如果我再婚 你怎么看
What would you say if I remarried?
很简单 我会杀了你
It's simple, I'd kill you.
想都不用想
No need to think.
你总是想那样过干净的日子
You always wanted a sanitized version of life.
我实话实说
You asked, I answered.
我会杀了你
I'd kill you.
你真是自私 真可怕
You're so selfish, it's frightening.
我知道
I know.
对了 这是你的支票
By the way, here's your check.
你从来不能真正把自己交出去
You never give anything truly of yourself.
- 你爸真是个考验  - 别说了
- Your father, it's such an ordeal?  - Don't.
- 他很老  - 可还有口气
- He's old.  - Still breathing.
真是老不死的
Some bonds never break.
从我进屋来就没好事
I walk in and it's one horror after another.
他有假释听证会
He has a parole hearing.
够了 行了吗
That's enough. Okay?
你的猛男忘了他的岔气带
Your stud forgot his hernia belt.
- 需要帮忙吗  - 不用了
- You need a hand?  - No, I've got it.
够大吗
ls it big enough?
再高的话 星星会划了天花板
Any taller and the star will scrape the ceiling.
米歇尔
Michèle!
晚上好
Evening.
在这儿能看到你太好了
I'm so glad I caught you. Here...
我在发这个
I'm handing these out.
是有关委员会垃圾分类的决议
It's about the Board's trash separation policy.
谢谢
Thank you.
违规的罚款太高了
The fines for non-compliance are exorbitant.
我们周三集合 去反对它
We're meeting Wednesday to oppose it.
你就是委员会成员 对吗
You're on the Board, aren't you?
- 对  - 我想指出来
- Yes.  - I've tried to point out
那个小的利益冲突
that minor conflict of interest.
那样的位置挺尴尬
It's an interesting position.
是的 的确是
Yes, that's right. Exactly.
希望你能来
I hope you can make it.
也许能去
Perhaps.
- 晚安  - 晚安
- Goodnight.  - Goodnight.
我再把这些发了
I'll just deliver these.
很快回来
Be right back!
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Good evening.  - Good evening.
最后一个了 钥匙在桌子上
Last one. Your new keys are on the table.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你注意到后门会卡住吗
Did you notice the back door jams?
我只修锁
I only do locks.
怎么会
How come?
好吧
Okay.
你怎么到那儿去了
How'd you get out there?
快进来
Come on in.
你不能对付他至少给他点厉害啊
You didn't have to claw his eyes out but scratch him at least.
我只是这么说说
I'm just saying.
未知来电 你这个年纪 身材已经很火辣了
I found you very narrow, for a woman of your age
那个二十五
That one's 25.
那是安全天使
That's the Safety Angel.
- 最强力的吗  - 非常有效
- The most powerful?  - Serious stuff.
零点二盎司防狼喷雾 时速一百一十迈
0.2 oz of pepper spray at 110 mph.
让你处于优势地位
Gives you quite an advantage.
我要了
I'll take it.
还有这个
And this.
你好
Hey, you!
你告诉文森特你给他付房租吗
You told Vincent you'd pay his rent?
没有 我只是说帮他一段时间
No, I said I'd help out for a while.
卡沙先生 可以入座了
Mr. Casamayou, your table's ready.
别想让我掏钱 我已经破产了
Don't expect me to pitch in. I'm stone broke.
是我答应的
I'm the one who made the promise.
图什么
Why?
勉强度日会培养人格
Struggling to get by builds character.
问题是 他女朋友是个神经病
Trouble is, he's dating a psycho.
多谢
Thank you very much.
那个神经病过不了苦日子
The wacko won't tolerate struggling.
通常神经病这个词
Psycho's the word.
描述的女孩 床上功夫都很厉害
Often though, that kind of girl's good in bed.
什么叫床上功夫厉害
What does that even mean, " good in bed" ?
- 我不知道  - 你看了我的提议了吗
- l never knew.  - You read my proposal?
理查德 你认为我这个年纪 我紧致吗
Richard, would you say I'm tight for a woman my age?
你们好
Hi there!
- 你好  - 谢谢能来
- Hi.  - Thanks.
怎么样 败类
What's up, loser?
亲爱的 你好吗
How are you, pumpkin?
正好赶上听米歇尔不愿意聊我游戏的事
Just in time to hear Michèle avoid giving her thoughts on my game idea.
不不 非常有趣
No! It was very interesting.
当然有趣
You bet it's interesting.
说吧
Tell all.
- 香槟酒四杯  - 不 来一瓶
- Bubbly, 4 glasses.  - No. a bottle!
这个背景是 狗被一种病毒灭掉了
It's set in a time when dogs have been wiped out by a virus.
人们就养机器狗作为宠物
So people have robotic canines as pets.
玩家是机器狗世界里的斯巴达克斯
The player's the Spartacus of the robot-dog world.
有新意
Original.
有意思
Interesting.
我想和你们说
I have something to tell you all.
我在想怎么样简单自然地
I was looking for a way of simply and naturally
和你们说 可我想不到
tossing this out. but I can't find one.
所以
So...
就直说吧我在家
Here goes. I was assaulted
被侵犯了
at home.
我应该是被强奸了
I guess I was raped.
强奸
Raped?
- 天啊  - 真的吗
- Oh my god.  - For real?
什么时候
When?
周四 下午三点
Thursday, at 3pm.
你没有和任何人说过
And you never said?
我不知道说什么 能说什么
I don't know what to say. What can I say?
天啊
Oh my god!
- 我不该说的  - 你疯了吗
- l feel stupid for bringing it up.  - Are you insane?
白雪香槟
A Piper-Heidsieck.
很好
Very good.
等几分钟再开吧
Wait a few minutes before popping it.
你还好吗
Are you alright?
你得去看医生
You have to see a doctor.
看过了
Done that.
警察怎么说
What did the cops say?
你没报警
You didn't report it?
米歇尔 你得赶紧报警
Michèle, you have to report it immediately.
为什么
What for?
What for!
没事了 不需要再谈这个了
It's over. It doesn't need talking about anymore.
都不值得讨论了
It's not worth a debate.
我们来点菜吧
How about we order?
你不想报警因为
You avoid the police because...
当然我不报警是因为
Of course I avoid the police "because!''
我再也不想和警察打交道了
I won't deal with the police ever again.
- 再见  - 再见
- See you!  - See you!
- 我给你把枪  - 枪 你疯了吗
- I'll get you a gun.  - A gun! You're out of your mind.
理查德 我要告诉你
Richard. I should tell you...
你的提议 我们的投资人不感兴趣
Your proposal, our investors aren't interested.
我现在不想聊这个
I don't want to discuss it now.
但是我想听听你的意见
But I'd like your opinion on it.
这和你产品的质量无关
It's got nothing to do with the quality of your work.
这是有特定受众的买卖
It's a business that's tied into a particular demographic.
一群不在乎产品质量的受众吗
A demographic oblivious to quality?
没错
Exactly.
没事我能接受
Come on, I can take it!
说实话 你到底觉得怎么样
Be honest. What did you think of it?
理查德 回去写你的小说 你是作家
Richard, go back to your novel. You're a writer.
是吗 一个身无分文的作家
Sure. A penniless writer.
有人把你的挡泥板撞坏了
Somebody trashed your fender.
有人
Somebody?
再见
See you.
该死
Shit!
这个给您 快捷团队
Here you go.
我马上出来
I'll be right there, I...
我去拿夹克
I'll just grab my jacket.
我的圣代在你那儿吧
You got my sundae?
谢谢 明天见
Thanks. See you tomorrow.
这个 给你
Here, for you.
- 给我的  - 对 我自己做的
- For me?  - Yes, made it myself.
好贴心啊
That's so sweet.
- 好吃  - 还不错吧 对吗
- Delicious.  - Not bad, right?
勒布朗女士 您好
Mrs. Leblanc? Hello.
你好
Hello
我是菲利普 中介的人
I'm Philippe, from the agency.
文森特 来得正好 我需要你
Vincent, good timing, I need you here.
你好 米歇尔
Hey, Michèle.
- 要我做什么  - 靠墙站着
- What can I do?  - Stand against the wall.
- 这样吗  - 对
- Yeah?  - Yeah.
你的胳膊
With your arms...
书架一米五宽 我想想象一下
The bookcase is 5 feet wide. I want to visualize it.
像这样可以吗
Like this, okay?
文森特
Vincent...
不要比划 就当你是书架
Don't act the bookcase. Be the bookcase.
好的 拿着
Okay, hold this.
文森特真是个好演员
Vincent is quite the actor.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
- 没事  - 没事的
- No.  - No, it's fine.
十二岁的时候他是克隆纳斯的阿基里斯
Age 12, he was young Achilles in Kronos.
一个我出品的视频游戏
A video game I produced.
真的吗
Yeah?
我猜你是最可爱的销甲骑士
I bet you were the cutest knight in armor.
还不错
Not too shabby.
挺好的吧
Nice, huh?
有点太好了 你们觉得呢
A little too nice, don't you think?
这里还有约一米三的空间
There's room for a 50-inch here.
你问她了吗
Did you ask her?
你说过一个微波炉
You mentioned a microwave,
但我们觉得电视可能是更好的暖房礼物
but we thought a TV makes a better housewarming present.
比起电视 你们不是更需要烤箱吗
Don't you need an oven more than a TV?
我们不需要 厨房里挺齐全的
We don't need one. The kitchen comes fully equipped.
这是你和我说过的公寓吗
ls this the apartment you told me about?
不是 这是两居室
No, it's a 2-bedroom here.
一个月两百五十美元租金
$250 a month more.
另一个太烂了 都没地方放婴儿床
The other one was a dump. Nowhere to put a crib.
太糟糕了
Totally insane.
太烂了 我不觉得
Dump, I don't think so.
可能只是简单了点
Basic, maybe.
但肯定不是烂
Dump, definitely not.
好吧 简单
Basic, sure.
你知道要孩子就是受罪了吗
You realize having a child is all about suffering?
文森特出生的时候就是场灾难
Vincent's birth was sheer hell.
折磨
Torture.
三个小时的折磨
Three hours of agony.
如果你不想帮我们 就别帮
If you don't want to help us, don't.
没人强迫你
Nobody's forcing you.
没我 你们怎么办
How'll you get by if I don't?
那是我们的事
That's our problem.
你不能拿了我的钱 还那样和我说话
You can't talk to me like that and take my money.
我才不在乎你的钱
I don't give a shit about your money.
我从没要过
I never asked for it.
你就只知道傻站着 什么也不说
You just stand there, saying nothing, as usual!
真是的 你什么时候才能像个男人
It's bullshit! When are you going to get off your ass?
别管闲事
Butt out, you!
你知道这不可能吧
You realize that this is impossible?
- 什么  - 她是个疯子
- What?  - She's a lunatic.
她不是 她是我女朋友
She's not. she's my girlfriend.
你就是看不到我的改变
You refuse to see I've changed.
现在感觉怎么样
What do you feel now?
恐惧还是生气
Fear or anger?
生气
Anger.
你错过你老婆了 安娜今天去昂古莱姆了
You've missed your wife. Anna's in Angoulême today.
你已经知道了
And you knew it.
你知道我有过创伤经历
You know I went through a traumatic experience
就在最近
recently.
你让人觉得你很坚强 什么都没发生
You gave the impression of soldiering on like nothing happened.
我很抱歉 如果我看上去有点麻木
If I seem insensitive, I'm sorry.
那就是我 不是吗
That's just me, right?
我看你是沉浸在角色中而已
I see you're staying in character.
我角色的一大部分
A big part of my character
就是不可琢磨
is being unpredictable.
稍等
Hold on.
你最近发生什么事了吗
Say, have you experienced any incidents recently?
什么事
Incidents?
你知道我在说什么
You know what I mean.
一个男的从车里向我扔比萨 没扔到
A man threw pizza at me from his car. He missed.
人们在市场盯着我看
People were staring at me at the market.
但我总有那种感觉
But I always feel that.
我想是不是不会重新开始了
I wonder if it isn't starting again.
新的循环
A new cycle.
你不知道吗
You don't know?
你父亲那集《被告起立》上周六又播了
The Accused Will Rise about your father aired again last Saturday.
- 人们又重温了一下  - 我不知道啊
- Refreshes people's memories.  - I'd no idea.
你呢
And you?
发生什么事了吗
Anything happened?
没 没什么
No, nothing special.
是因为他的假释听证会
It's because of his parole hearing.
那可是大热的新闻材料
A media feeding frenzy.
下周他就要上庭了
He's up before the judge next week.
你不会错过的
You don't miss a beat.
两杯咖啡 谢谢
Two coffees, please.
和我一起来
Come with me.
他们永远不会放他出来 谢天谢地
They'll never let him out. Thank god!
假释听证会就是猜字谜游戏
The parole hearing is a charade.
明知我宁愿把眼睛挖出来
Like you telling me to come,
你却还叫我和你一起去
when you know I'd rather gouge my eyes out.
你准备要恨多久
How long will you hang on to hatred?
我这辈子 下辈子都不准备见他了
I'll never see him again, in this world or any other.
- 好吧 没下辈子了  - 您的咖啡
- Anyway, there is no other.  - Your coffee.
- 剩余时间不多了  - 谢谢
- There isn't much time left.  - Thanks.
他病了
He's ill.
看
Look...
就看一眼
Look, just for one moment.
你害怕看你自己的亲生父亲吗
You're afraid to look at your own father?
收好吧
Put it away now.
你不是那些暴徒
You're not like the mob.
他们只知道他是恶魔
People who only know the monster.
你认识这个人 他只是个人
You know the man. He's just a man.
只是碰巧做了坏事
Who happens to be a monster.
你看到这矛盾了吗
You see a contradiction there?
喝了吧 我已经喝完了
Drink up. I'm done here.
小心点
Be careful, won't you?
有些人不只从他们车里
Some people won't just toss crap
往外扔垃圾
from their cars.
马蒂
Marty!
给我那只鸟
Give me that bird.
马蒂
Marty!
我们不治野生的鸟 是麻雀吗
We don't treat wild birds. It's a sparrow?
是的
Yes.
我甚至不知道怎么给它插管子
I wouldn't even know how to intubate your sparrow.
如果那是只麻雀的话
If it is a sparrow.
多谢了
Thanks very much.
再见
Goodbye.
没事的 再见
You're welcome. Goodbye.
被告起立 里格街谋杀案 各种年龄的受害者
...victims of all ages.
今天的南斯郊区 安静的街道
Seen today, this quiet street in the suburbs of Nantes
已看不出这里曾发生过何等暴行
bears no trace of the atrocities that took place here
三十九年前
39 years ago.
今天的住户没有几个人知道
Few of today's inhabitants
乔治·勒布朗 这个名字
know the name, Georges Leblanc.
或者很少有人知道
Or if they do,
那是一个和恐怖故事有关的名字
it's a name associated with a horror story
他们很少有人记得
that they can hardly remember.
那是别的时代的城市传说
An urban folktale from another time.
然而 一九七六年时
And yet, in 1976,
法国人的眼睛都盯着这条街
the eyes of France were trained on this street.
整个国家都屏住了呼吸
A nation held its breath.
震惊
In shock.
时间让人遗忘了曾经那
Time has dulled the terror
五月一天里的恐惧
of that distant day in May.
但对有些人来说 那恐惧不会减少
But for some the horror will never fade away.
那些未解之谜也不会褪色
Nor will the unanswered questions.
什么让乔治·勒布朗
What drove Georges Leblanc,
一个虔诚的天主教徒
a practising Catholic,
慈爱的丈夫 父亲
loving husband and father,
犯下如此重罪
to commit such monstrous and senseless acts?
他女儿米歇尔到底扮演了什么角色
And what role exactly was played by his daughter, Michèle?
她当时只有十岁
A ten-year-old child at the time.
在数年审讯和精神评估之后
After years of trials and psychiatric evaluations,
乔治·勒布朗已经在监狱度过了三十年
over 30 years after Georges Leblanc's incarceration,
终身监禁
sentenced to life,
问题仍然没有得到解答
the questions remain,
虽然过去很久 但仍然令人毛骨护谏然
as banal yet chilling as ever.
首先也是最重要的
First and foremost...
为什么
Why?
杀人犯
Murderer!
希望那个是可回收的
I hope that's recyclable.
那是只死鸟
It's a dead bird.
理查德
Richard!
你是怎么想的
What were you thinking?
我很担心你
I was worried about you.
上帝
Jesus!
别揉你的眼睛
Don't rub your eyes.
你说你被强奸了 但也不报警
You say you were raped and didn't report it,
显然我得
obviously I'm going to...
天啊 你真把我弄伤了
Holy shit, you really did a number on me!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
那有用吗 你知道你在做什么吗
That helps? You know what you're doing?
那在防狼喷雾的商标上
It's on the pepper spray label.
可能 我会瞎的
Could be, I'll go blind.
当然不会瞎
Of course, you won't go blind!
好了
There we go.
- 来杯红酒  - 好
- Glass of wine?  - Yes. please.
我没认出那辆车 那是谁的
I didn't recognize the car. Whose is it?
朋友的
A friend's.
女朋友的吗
A girl friend's?
- 她的名字叫海琳  - 海琳
- Her name's Hélène.  - Hélène.
我借她的 我的车在店里
I borrowed hers. Mine's in the shop.
有人把保险杠撞坏了
Somebody smashed the bumper.
几乎看不出来
It was barely visible.
她只是个朋友 米歇尔
She's a friend, Michèle.
我为什么要澄清这个呢
Why am I even justifying this?
你没有必要澄清什么
You have nothing to justify.
- 她是学生吗  - 研究生
- She's a student?  - Grad student.
挺让人惊讶
Surprise me.
她不是我的学生 她组织博瓦尔研讨会
She's not my student. She organizes a De Beauvoir seminar.
她邀请我去发言
She invited me to speak.
她读过你的书
And she's read your book.
她读过
She's read it.
她告诉我她被深深地打动了
And told me how deeply it touched her,
我心都快化了
I melted inside.
就是这些 其余的事你可以想象
That's all. You can imagine the rest.
其实我倒是真能想象到
I can imagine just fine, actually.
你真的没有必要嫉妒
Your jealousy is insane.
没有 我只是关心而已
No, I'm just concerned.
我关心因为这是我害怕的
I'm concerned because this is what I feared.
大胸又不检点的女人 我倒不担心
The bimbos with big tits never worried me,
但是读《第二性》的女人会把你吃了
but a woman who's read The Second Sex will chew you up
然后再把你吐出来
and spit you out.
真正的危险是你 米歇尔
The real danger, Michèle, is you.
你认识她吗
Did you know about her?
认识 我见过她一次
Yeah, I met her once.
什么时候的事
When was that?
上周 我们在爸爸那儿一起吃饭
Last week. We all had dinner at Dad's.
怎么没听你提起过
Why didn't you mention it?
我不知道
I dunno...
乔西 把那个放下 我来弄
Josie, put that down. I'll do it.
什么时候
When?
和我说话能别分神吗
Can I have some focus here, please?
怎么了
What?
海琳是什么样的人
What's Hélène like?
她挺酷的 瑜伽教师 好像教高温瑜咖
She's cool. A yoga teacher. Bikram yoga, I think.
把你的脚挪开可以吗
Move your feet, will you?
在哪儿教
Where?
- 怎么了  - 我告诉埃里克他可以留着
- Why?  - l told Eric he could have it.
埃里克 谁是埃里克
Eric? Who's this Eric?
马雷瑜伽中心
Marais Yoga Center.
- 不能等会再说吗  - 把你的脚挪开
- Can't it wait?  - Move your feet!
你帮我拆包行吗
How about you help me unpack?
我马上来
I'll be right there.
十分钟后比赛结束
The fight'll be over in 10 minutes.
接下来是足球比赛
And soccer next up.
乔西 你要去哪儿
Josie! Where are you going?
文森特 我再打给你
Vincent, I'll call you back.
好的 再见
Yeah. bye.
看到了吗
Seen it?
整个办公室都看到了
It was sent to the whole office?
看看
Take a look.
这不是他第一次发给我东西
This isn't the first thing he's sent me.
谁给你发的东西
First thing who's sent you?
那个袭击你的人
The guy who attacked you?
是的
Of course.
你觉得可能吗 强奸你的人
You think that's possible? Your attacker?
邮件看上去是从这里发出的
I mean, the email seems to come from here.
看着像
Looks like it.
赶紧给警察打电话
Call the police now.
警察 绝不 没有用的
The police, never again. It's pointless.
这次不一样 你是受害者
This is different. You're the victim.
那时候我也是受害者
I was the victim then!
对不起 我
Sorry, I...
我不想警察卷进来
I don't want the police involved.
我不会让这个白痴把那些破事搅起来
I won't let this cretin stir up all that shit.
我努力重建生活 不让警察 记者
I fought too hard to rebuild my life, so police, journalists...
没门
No way.
上帝保佑
God help us.
有个疯子在周围
There's a nutjob out there.
疯子 我可以搞定 那是我的专长
Nutjobs, I can handle. My specialty.
我们服务器六月就被攻击过
When our server was hacked in June,
有人把克苏鲁板从主机上拆下来
somebody ripped the Cthulhu template off our mainframe.
类似于这样的图像就从那时候开始出现
Images like these have floated around since then.
我的秘密崇拜者
My secret admirer
肯定是个高科技能人
must be highly tech savvy.
- 之前的雇员吗  - 有可能
- A former employee maybe?  - Yeah.
最后一个问题 你觉得她美吗
Last question. You think she's pretty?
弯腰 从背部很低的位置开始
Bend forward, from low in your back.
朝着地板 伸展你的脊椎
Stretch your spine all the way to the floor.
深呼吸
Deep breath.
左手推地板 逐渐坐起来
Push the floor with your left hand until seated again.
谢谢大家
Thank you all very much.
祝今天愉快 非常棒
Have a good day. Excellent work.
鞠躬
Namaste.
海琳
Hélène?
我是米歇尔 理查德的前任
I'm Michèle. Richard's ex.
- 很高兴见到你  - 你好
- Nice to meet you.  - Hello.
希望没有打扰到你
Hope you don't mind me barging in.
我想来当面道歉
I wanted to apologize face to face.
为什么呢
For what?
你的车窗 抱歉
Your car window. I'm sorry.
没事的 理查德都和我解释了
Please. it's nothing. Anyway, Richard explained it all.
是吗 他怎么说的
Really? What was his explanation?
他说是个事故
It was an accident.
对 是个事故
Yes, that's right. An accident.
很高兴见到你
And a good chance to meet you.
是的 太棒了
Yes, great!
终于见到你了 震撼
It's wonderful finally meeting you.
- 我在想  - 理查德不用给我们介绍了
- l was thinking...  - Richard won't have to introduce us.
我们避免了尴尬
We've dodged an awkward situation.
为什么说是尴尬呢
Why would it be awkward?
那个
Well...
当然 你是对的 确实
Of course, you're right, it's...
我觉得我们可以
I guess we could have...
- 我的意思是  - 都已经过去了
- l mean...  - But it's behind us now.
没错
Exactly!
我们以后应该三个人一起聚聚
We should get together some time, all of us.
对 我要开一个圣诞聚会
Yes. I'm having a Christmas party.
你一定要来
You really must come.
一起来吧
Come along.
恭敬不如从命
If I must.
具体的我会告诉理查德 我该走了
I'll give Richard the details. I should get going.
见到你太开心了
Lovely to meet you.
是的 我也是
Yes, lovely to have met you.
- 再见  - 再见
- Goodbye.  - Goodbye.
喂
Hello?
皇家港 现在吗
Port Royal, right now?
真的吗
Really?
她一直在出血 他们做了超音波
She was losing blood. They did an ultrasound.
- 她有  - 胎盘早剥
- She has a...  - A placental abruption.
他们说没问题 正在引产
They say it's okay but they're inducing labor.
- 噢  - 奥马尔 我的一个哥们
- Oh  - Omar, a buddy of mine.
- 你好  - 爸爸
- Hello.  - Dad!
- 现在怎么样了  - 还不知道
- What's the news?  - Nothing yet.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
我在这儿
I'm right here.
- 我害怕  - 没事的
- I'm scared.  - It's gonna be okay.
好痛啊
It hurts!
我去拿一杯咖啡
I'll go get a coffee.
深呼吸
Deep breaths.
该死 好痛啊
Fuck, it hurts!
怎么突然间你要办圣诞聚会了
So suddenly you're throwing a Christmas party?
我觉得是了解彼此的好机会
I thought it'd be good to get to know each other better.
对了 她很可爱
She's lovely, by the way.
又是你的一个圈套吗
Another of your traps?
我还有别的事 没空计划恶毒的圣诞聚会
I have better things to do than plot diabolical Christmas dinners.
她有忌口的东西吗 对什么过敏
ls there anything she won't eat? Any allergies?
那猫掉毛掉得厉害
The cat's shedding like crazy.
你的小提琴家我都从没抱怨过
I made no fuss about your violinist.
那不一样
That was different!
他已婚 有三个孩子 条件都满足
He was married with 3 kids. He checked every box.
她年轻 单身 年龄正适合要孩子
She's a young, single woman of child-bearing age.
你违背了所有的约定
You've broken all the rules.
我第一次听说约定 不是我的错
First I heard we had an agreement. It's not my fault if...
是你的错 我们应该还在一起的
It is your fault. We should still be together.
- 是你的错  - 是你离开我的
- It's your fault.  - You left me.
你打了我
You hit me.
如果我这辈子有后悔的事 就是那个了
If there's one thing in my life I regret, it's that.
生了
All done!
- 生了吗  - 是的
- All done?  - Yes.
我们得去做DNA检测
We're going to need a DNA test.
- 要抱孩子进来吗  - 马上
- Are they bringing him in?  - Right now.
我会是个好妈妈的
I'll be a good mother to him.
傻子 你会是最棒的妈妈
Silly! You'll be awesome!
要我们出去吗
Should we go?
不用
No.
没事
It's fine.
有很多人
Lots of people here.
大家好
Hey, everybody!
骄傲的父亲
Who's a proud Daddy!
真是个小奇迹 他真漂亮
A little marvel! Isn't he handsome!
快看看他
Look at that!
这是我生儿子的地方
This is where I had my son.
就在这个妇产中心
In this maternity unit.
真有趣
That's funny.
倒不是 令人惊异的是
Not really. The amazing thing is,
我的朋友安娜
my friend Anna...
- 你刚刚见过她了  - 是的
- You saw her up there, you met her.  - Yes.
她和我同一个晚上生的孩子
She gave birth here that same night.
这是我们见面的地方
This is where we met.
她的孩子是死胎 她要帮我的孩子喂奶
Her child was still born. She asked to breastfeed mine.
天啊
Oh my!
我和她说 可以
I said to her, fine.
自那以后 我就总想
Since then, I've often wondered.
安娜和我的儿子
They've always been very close.
关系很亲近
Anna and my son.
我想会不会有某种铭记
I wonder if there wasn't some kind of
就像鸭子一样
imprinting, like with ducks.
然而 和我呢
With me. on the other hand...
- 你知道  - 抱歉 他们在呼我
- You know...  - Sorry, they're paging me.
有时候我看到文森特
Sometimes I look at Vincent,
一无所长的粗人
the big lout with nothing special about him
他是从我的肚子里出来的
that came out of my belly,
我得承认 我不了解他
and I have to admit I don't know him.
- 晚上好 米歇尔  - 晚上好 瑞贝卡
- Evening, Michèle.  - Evening, Rebecca.
帕特里克陪你进去吧 有个小偷
Patrick will walk you inside. There's a prowler.
- 是吗  - 帕特里克和他打了一架
- There is?  - Patrick fought with him.
- 小偷  - 是的
- A prowler?  - Yes.
他们要派三辆车来对付他
They're sending 3 cars after the creep.
你和他打了一架
You fought with him?
我见他蹲在这儿的灌木丛里
I caught him crouched in the bushes,
往你屋子里望
watching your house.
我走近的时候 他开始跑
When I approached, he took off.
你看到他的脸了吗
You saw his face?
没有 他戴着面具 像是滑雪面具
No, he was wearing a mask, like a ski mask.
就像电视剧里的跟踪者
Like a stalker on a TV show.
他跑了
He got away.
帕特 陪她进去吧
Pat, go in with her.
不 不麻烦了
No, don't bother.
- 还是去吧  - 好吧 马上回来
- Do it anyway.  - Okay, be right back.
真的没有关系 真的
It's really not necessary, honestly.
我屋里有防狼喷雾
I have pepper spray in the house.
好
Good to know.
灯的开关在你左边
Light switch on your left there.
看上去一切都好
Everything seems to be okay.
谢谢你 我很感激
Thanks, anyway. I appreciate it.
没事的 我又没做什么
No problem, I didn't do much.
我差点抓住他了
I nearly caught him,
不过他跑得太快了
but he took off so fast.
高中时 我跑一千米才用两分四十二秒
In high school, I ran the 1,000 meters in 2'42''.
可能他的速度说明了他有多怕你
Perhaps his speed shows how scared he was of you.
谢谢你救了我的自尊
Thank you for salvaging my pride.
不客气
You're welcome.
那
Well...
看到或者听到什么 就大声叫
See anything or hear anything, just shout.
Okay.
我当奶奶了
I'm a grandmother.
- 恭喜你啊  - 谢谢了
- Congratulations.  - Thank you.
天啊 我为什么说这个
God knows why I said that.
早上好 米歇尔
Morning, Michèle.
我很喜欢你的上衣
I like your sweater.
你滑雪吗
Do you ski?
当然
Sure.
我随时可以带你去
I'll take you anytime.
凯文
Kevin?
你会打枪对吧
You shoot, right?
我是说真正的打枪
I mean. real shooting.
是的 没错
That's right, I do.
你有枪吗
You own guns?
有两把
A couple.
你能教教我吗
Could you teach me?
没问题 我可以教你
I could show you, sure.
真实生活中 这样就行了
In real life, that'd do the job.
真实生活中 他会跑得更快
In real life, he'd run faster.
确实
True.
试试四四口径的
Try the .44 now.
凯文 我还想和你聊聊
Kevin, I also wanted to talk to you
因为我有一份私人的任务给你
because I've got an unofficial assignment for you.
那个黑客
A black op?
我想知道是谁做的那个动画
I want to know who created that animation.
你知道我说的是哪个吧
You know the one I mean?
黑进整个办公室里人们的家用电脑
Hack into the home computers of the whole office.
至少要查所有男士的
All the guys, at least.
我想帮忙 可那是违规的
I want to help, but that's a major violation.
我给你一万现金
I'm offering $10,000 cash in hand.
就当是你我之间的秘密
Between you and me. Our secret.
你这么查别人 会发现奇怪的事情的
When you snoop on people, you turn up some weird shit.
我知道 我不会另眼看他们
I know. I won't judge.
这个放哪儿
Where does this one go?
就放在这里
Put it right there.
我解开那一个 试一下
I untangled that one. Try it.
- 这个吗  - 右边那个 等会我弄另一个
- This one?  - On the right. I'll do the other next.
- 你好 瑞贝卡  - 嗨 米歇尔
- Hi, Rebecca!  - Hi. Michèle.
太漂亮了
Beautiful!
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Evening.  - Evening.
耶稣的诞生每次都会感动到我
The Nativity gets me every time. Where it all began.
没错
Very true.
我知道现在才邀请你有点不礼貌
I know it's rude to invite you last minute,
不过我明天要办圣诞派对
but I'm having a Christmas get-together tomorrow.
帕特里克 你听到了吗
Patrick, did you hear that?
是的
Yeah.
太好了
With pleasure.
是啊 我们非常愿意去
Yes, with pleasure, absolutely.
那
Well then...
明天见
See you tomorrow.
- 明天见  - 明天见
- See you then.  - See you then.
谢谢你
Thank you.
理论上 我们可以给理查德爱人那份
In theory, we could put a toothpick
里面插一根牙签
inside one for Richard's ladylove.
或者毒死她
Or just poison her.
她该能预见的 她已经觉得我是毒妇了
She has me pegged as a Medea, She'd see it coming.
充满了嫉妒
consumed by jealousy.
她也是古典文学专业的吗
She was a classics major, too?
- 乔西  - 罗伯特
- Josie.  - Robert.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
- 好 爸爸  - 太好了
- Okay, Dad?  - Great.
嗨 孩子
Hi, kiddo.
天啊 他臭死了 抱着
Jeez, he stinks. Here!
你怎么样
How you doing?
你要把我们都震聋吗 小心点
You trying to deafen us all with your shit? Careful.
大家好
Hello, all!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
如果我变成那样 就杀了我吧
If I ever show up like that, kill me.
晚上好
Evening!
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Evening!  - Evening!
抱歉我们晚了 我在挖一瓶
Sorry we're late. I was digging out a great...
失陪
Excuse me.
赤霞珠红葡萄酒
Cabernet.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Evening!  - Evening!
拼字游戏啊
Scrabble party!
谢谢
Thank you.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Evening!  - Evening!
最近有状况吗
Any more alerts?
没有 那个恶人不理我们了
No, the bogeyman's deserted us.
反正今晚我们是安全的
Anyway, we're safe tonight.
我三月拿到了红带
I got my red belt in March.
练空手道之前 我练了很久跄拳道
I did Taekwondo for years before switching to Shotokan.
我从来没练过空手道
I've never done karate.
她取笑我呢
She was making fun of me.
好吧
Ok.
你总不能一晚上不理我吧
You can't avoid me all night.
你想打赌吗
Want a bet?
很高兴你们能来
I'm glad you made it.
我们不怎么应酬
We don't get out much.
不过瑞贝卡很喜欢聚会
Unfortunately for Rebecca, who's a very social person.
和我不一样
Unlike me.
很高兴她今天把你给拽过来了
I'm glad she dragged you over here tonight.
那没什么难的
It was no hardship.
晚上好
Good evening!
抱歉我迟到了
So sorry I'm late.
工作脱不开身
I couldn't get off work.
我们也才坐下 嗨 海琳
We just sat down. Hi, Hélène.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Evening!  - Evening!
大家晚上好
Evening, everybody.
艾琳 这是海琳
lrène, this is Hélène.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Evening!  - Evening!
- 晚上好 我是拉尔夫  - 晚上好
- Evening. I'm Ralf.  - Evening.
大家随意
Well, enjoy your meal!
谢谢
Thanks.
抱歉了
I'm sorry...
我想先祷告 你们介意吗
I'd like to say grace, if nobody objects.
当然不会 请吧
Of course not. Please do.
谢谢了
Thank you.
上帝保佑我们 谢谢恩赐的食物
Bless us, Lord, and bless this meal.
给饥饿的人面包
And provide bread to the needy.
阿门
Amen.
- 阿门  - 阿门
- Amen.  - Amen.
要红酒吗 米歇尔
Wine, Michèle?
是的 谢谢
With pleasure.
帕特里克 你是做什么的
So, Patrick, what do you do?
我做银行业的
I work in banking.
我是个经纪人 我有罪
I'm a broker. And I plead guilty.
为什么呢
How come?
开玩笑呢 现在这工作不太受欢迎
Just joking. It's not a popular profession right now.
从来都这样
It never was.
- 或许吧  - 各位
- l guess not.  - Well.
祝圣诞快乐
To Christmas!
敬我们
And to us!
尤其是新加入我们的成员
Especially the newcomers to our table...
艾琳
lrène,
帕特里克
Patrick,
瑞贝卡
Rebecca.
拉尔夫
Ralf.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
米歇尔工作太劳累了
Michèle's worked like a trooper.
的确是
Absolutely.
我很爱烹饪
I love cooking.
你什么时候去
When are you going?
我准备订
I'll try to book the...
但是我们想选的时间 票很紧俏
But the period we want books up fast.
人们没有意识到艺术是需要培养的
People don't realize the art muscle needs training.
否则文化就会坍塌 变得差劲
Or else culture collapses, goes flabby.
现在就这样 差劲的文化
That's what we've got now. Flabby culture.
是在说我吗
Is that aimed at me?
曾经会追求
Originality or singularity
原创性和奇特性
used to be valued and sought after.
或者甚至是本身的结局 现在就是责任了
Or even an end in itself. Now it's a liability.
理查德是个理论家
Richard's a theorist.
我说的不是创新
I'm not talking about novelty.
还创新 都是胡扯的
Coming out of our ass, novelty!
晚餐的美好景象
Delightful image at dinner.
灵感是什么百分之八十的努力工作
Anyway, what's inspiration? 80% hard work.
有的人根本不知道要努力工作
Some people know nothing of hard work.
他们文化里就没有这个
It's not in their culture.
我们知道你在说谁
We know who you mean.
我什么也没说
I didn't say a word.
不 我觉得 每个人都不同 我爱每个人
Everybody's different. I love everyone.
我们都是上帝的孩子
We're all children of God!
对 非洲人吃山羊内脏 他们不同
Yeah, Africans eat goat's innards. They're different.
没错
Exactly.
我去了肯尼亚旅行 非常棒
I went on safari in Kenya. It was great.
是的 就是的
Right, there you go.
我觉得现在说很合适
I think now is a good time.
我有个事要宣布
I have an announcement to make.
拉尔夫和我订婚了
Ralf and I are engaged to be married.
对不起
Sorry.
你怎么这么奇怪
How do you manage to be so grotesque?
你没意识到吗
Don't you realize?
希望大家都喜欢蓝萄
I hope everyone likes blueberries.
乔西比食谱要求的多加了好多蓝薄
Josie added a ton to the official recipe.
我想创新一下 所以多加了蓝荀
I was feeling creative, so I added blueberries.
看上去不错
Looks good to me.
快半夜了 你介意我放弥撒吗
It's almost midnight. Do you mind if I put on the Mass?
完全不介意
On the contrary.
你们要走了吗
You're leaving?
聚会很棒 真的
It was wonderful. Really.
下次我们来办 你来参加
Next time, our turn. You'll come to us.
咱们别急
Let's not rush things.
让我们来
Leave it to us.
米歇尔和我先一起吃午饭
We'll have lunch first, Michèle and I.
就我们两个人
Just the two of us.
一点点来
One step at a time.
我同意 好主意
I agree, excellent idea.
晚安
Goodnight.
Great.
- 再见  - 再见
- See you!  - See you!
再见
See you, 'night!
和银行小子调情 那是考验吗
Flirting with the banker, was that a test?
你在我家还胡闹 都到这个程度了吗
You're making a scene in my home? It's come to that?
- 我们再聊  - 做点有用的事
- We'll talk later.  - Make yourself useful.
灾难
Disaster!
- 那是两个两字词 －一个两字词
- That's two double words.  - One double word.
我比你的大
I can top that.
旅途
Journey!
- 六十四  - 等等 我来
- 64.  - Hold on, I've got it.
不，那是七十
No, that's 70.
七十 你看
70, you see.
怪我
My bad.
- 女士们  - 不用了 谢谢了
- Ladies...  - No, thanks.
- 确定吗  - 是的
- Sure?  - Really.
诅咒他吧 见鬼去吧
Curse him! Damn him!
合上书 按响铃 吹灭蜡烛
Close the book, ring the bell, blow out the candle.
那是什么
What's that?
还说自己是天主教徒
Call yourself a Catholic?
都不知道逐出教会的仪式
You don't know the excommunication rite?
你知道
And you do?
我听说过
I've heard about it.
在我去学校之前 我的父亲
My father made the sign of the cross on me,
给我做十字的手势
before I left for school.
他给所有本地的孩子都做
He did it to all the local kids
直到后来有些家长不愿意了
until some parents asked him to stop.
听起来很合理啊
Sounds reasonable.
显然 我的父亲被冒犯到了
Apparently, my father was offended.
那一晚 他出去走
That night. he made the rounds.
挨家挨户敲别人家的门
Knocked on every door,
走进街上的每一家
went into every house on the street
带着一把猎枪 一个屠夫棒
with a shotgun, a butcher's mallet
还有两把厨刀
and a pair of kitchen knives.
对 我听说过
Yes, I heard about that.
你只听说二十七个人类受害者 没说动物
You heard about the 27 human victims, not about the animals.
没有提到动物
They never get a mention.
还有六只狗
6 dogs,
几只猫
a couple of cats, too.
不知道为什么 他饶了一只仓鼠
For whatever reason, he spared a hamster.
这事你不能瞎编
You couldn't make it up.
他回来的时候我在做功课
I was doing my homework when he arrived home
他浑身全是血
with blood all over him.
我妈妈当时在工作
My mother was at work.
她那时是个护士
She was a nurse back then.
你能想到吗 我妈妈是个护士
Can you imagine my mother. a nurse?
很滑稽吧
Funny, isn't it?
我们没必要谈这个
We don't have to go over it.
我不介意 说出来让我感觉好一些
I don't mind. It does me good to talk.
他决定把屋子里所有的东西都烧了
He decided to burn everything in the house.
我帮忙点了火
I helped feed the fire.
我们把所有的都烧了 窗帘 地毯
We gutted the place. Curtains, carpets...
桌子 椅子
Tables, chairs...
所有都烧了
All in the fire.
那很让人兴奋
It was exciting. You get caught up in it.
正要烧我们的衣服时 警察来了
We were about to burn our clothes when the police arrived.
有人给我们拍了张照
Someone snapped a photo.
奇怪的是 那张照片让人们印象深刻
Bizarrely, it's that photo that stuck in people's minds.
我半裸着 浑身都是灰
Me, half-naked, smeared with ash.
一个精神病女孩的样子
The photo of a little girl as psychopath,
站在她父亲旁边
next to her father,
那个疯子
the psychopath.
照片里我空洞的眼神很恐怖
My empty stare in the photo is terrifying.
不赖吧
Not bad, huh?
要喝白兰地吗
Cognac?
- 好的  - 用同一个杯子行吗
- Love one.  - Same glass okay?
还有人要白兰地吗
Cognac anyone?
- 我 谢谢  - 威士忌
- Me, please.  - Whiskey.
- 香槟 谢谢  - 我没有了
- Champagne, please.  - I'm out.
一杯威士忌 一杯白兰地
So, one whiskey and one cognac.
你知道
Are you aware
刚刚你对我态度非常刻薄吗
how mean you were to me at dinner?
是的 我知道
Yes, I am.
你真是残忍
You're cruel
如果有事 有人让你不舒服
when you find anything or anyone unpleasant.
显然我就是其中之一
I'm on the list, apparently.
我们两个都不够醉 不该说这个
Neither of us is drunk enough for this conversation.
好吗
Okay?
- 艾琳  - 艾琳
- lrène!  - lrène!
怎么了
What's happened?
能听到我说话吗
Can you hear me?
难以置信
I don't believe it!
你最好信
You better believe it!
什么
What?
去看看
Go see...
你爸爸
your father.
她中风了
She's had a major stroke.
我们减轻了她的脑压 但她还是没反应
We alleviated the pressure on her brain but she remains unresponsive.
没有反应 什么意思
Unresponsive. meaning?
她陷入昏迷了
She is comatose.
昏迷多久
How long for?
对不起 我们不能确定
Sorry, there's no telling.
- 她状态比较稳定  - 真的吗
- l mean, she's stable...  - This is real?
什么
Excuse me?
我是说
No. I mean...
有没有可能她是在装
There's no way she's faking it or playing it up?
你们从医学角度确定这是中风吗
You're medically certain this is for real?
抱歉 但这是真的中风
I'm sorry, but yes it's for real.
其实 很可能你妈妈再也醒不过来了
In fact, there's a strong probability your mother will not wake up.
不过就像我说的 她现在状态很稳定
But as I say, she's stable right now.
我建议你回去休息一下
I suggest you get some rest.
你在这里也帮不上什么忙
There's nothing you can do here now.
如果有情况 我们马上通知你
We'll call you if there's any news.
再见 谢谢你
Goodbye and thank you.
坚强一点
Be strong.
怎么样
Well?
情况不好
It's not good.
你介意睡在客房吗
Do you mind sleeping in the guest room?
不介意
No.
你和我一起睡
You're sleeping with me.
你看到理查德和海琳了吗
Did you see Richard with Hélène?
看到了
I did.
还是老生常谈
Telling the same old stories.
但她还是总能被逗乐
And she seemed amused by them all.
你们会成为好朋友的
You'll wind up being good friends.
确实
No doubt.
我会过去吃饭 就我们三个人
I'll go over for dinner, just the three of us.
我想象 自己拿着一盒马卡龙站在他们门口
I picture myself at their door with a box of macaroons.
那样让我想吐
It makes me want to puke!
你记不记得在卡西斯
You remember in Cassis?
我们试了一下
We tried.
那时真是没救了 我们一直笑个不停
It was hopeless. we couldn't stop laughing.
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
安娜去上班了 我想让你高兴点
Anna's gone to the office. I was trying to cheer you up.
奇怪的是 你的愚蠢最先吸引了我
Oddly, your stupidity was what first attracted me.
如果我错了 我道歉
Sorry if I misjudged.
我不能再那样了 咱们停下
I can't do this anymore. We have to stop.
你哪里都好
You were great and everything.
我们还是朋友 但是
We'll stay friends but...
你是认真的吗
Are you kidding?
这个荒谬的事让人难以忍受 对吧
This whole ridiculous situation is unbearable, right?
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
没有
No.
你的胸部更大了
Your breasts are bigger.
我没感觉到
Not that I'm aware of.
我这就在告诉你呢
I'm telling you.
说你不需要我了 说我们结束了
Say you don't want me anymore and we're done.
没那么简单
It's not that simple.
如果你非要我说
But if you like...
我不想要那样了 那些谎言
I don't want this anymore, this situation, the lies.
不要躲避我的问题
You dodged my question.
对不起
Sorry.
我不想和你上床了
I don't want to fuck you anymore.
这样可以吗
Was that the question?
我不会去见他
I won't see him.
我又不迷信
I'm not superstitious.
我才不关心临终请求
I couldn't care less about death-bed requests.
如果你想继续用卑鄙手段控制我的话
If you hope to keep manipulating me with this abject stunt...
自从你开始不要脸面
Ever since you gave up on basic morality,
表现得像个被宠坏的小孩开始
acting out like a spoiled teenager,
你就从来不关心我想什么
you never gave a shit what I thought.
你让我多受伤
How much it hurt me.
你的动脉瘤不过是个手段
This aneurysm thing is just treachery.
恶心
Disgusting.
就像这个沙拉 带着破橄榄
Like this salad, with its shitty olives.
你不能一直都生我的气
You can't stay mad at me till the end.
好的 新闻频道没问题
Sure, the news channel works fine.
她心搏过速
She's in v-tach.
发生什么了
What's going on?
那响声是什么意思
What's that beep?
女士 请
Ma'am. please.
心搏骤停
Cardiac arrest!
二十毫克硝酸甘油
20 mg of GTN.
无效 升到四十
No change. Up it to 40!
还是没有反应
Still no change.
她要不行了
We're losing her.
你干什么 对不起 我情不自禁
What are you doing?
我想找一个风景好些的地方
I'm looking for a spot with some significance.
又不是会有地方标记着
It's not like there'll be a sign that says,
此处可丢弃妈妈
"Dispose of mother here."
他的奶嘴呢
His pacifier.
我们在那个洞那儿野餐过一次
We had a picnic there once, that hollow there.
我记得很清楚
I remember only too well.
她的鸡肉沙拉害我放臭屁
Her chicken salad gave me horrific gas.
你忘记了吗
You forgot it?
你怎么这么白痴
How can you be such an idiot?
我提醒了你三次
Three times I reminded you.
在家还有在车上 你很享受吗
At home and in the car. You enjoy this?
看她怎么和他说话
See how she talks to him?
不要想游戏机了 傻子
Give up the Xbox, moron!
给我闭嘴
Stop it.
闭嘴 闭什么嘴
Stop it? Stop what?
我让你难堪了吗
I'm embarrassing you?
都是你自找的 浑蛋
All you deserve, asshole!
产后忧郁症
Baby blues.
我希望我儿子不要遗传她的脾气
I hope my boy doesn't inherit her temperament.
文森特
Vincent,
他很可爱 但他不是你儿子 你知道吧
he's cute but he's not your son. You know that, right?
找到了
Found it.
乔西
Josie!
你在听吗
Are you listening?
怎么了
What's up?
他不是你儿子
He's not your son.
看看他皮肤的颜色
Look at his skin.
比你和乔西的肤色深两个色号
It's two tones darker than yours or Josie's.
你看不出来吗
Don't you see?
- 他不是我儿子是谁儿子  - 是别人的
- Whose is he, if he's not mine?  - He's his father's!
他的父亲不是你
His father's not you.
对不起 但是你被耍了
Sorry, but you're being made a fool of.
别碰我
Don't lay a finger on me.
贱人
Cunt!
什么 你再说一遍
What? Say that again.
贱人
Cunt!
- 什么  - 贱人
- What?  - Cunt!
文森特
Vincent
站住
Stop!
我知道你很生气
I know why you're angry.
让我静一静
Leave me alone.
接下来怎么办
So what now?
好 这样应该可以了
Okay, this'll have to do.
风把它吹起来了
The wind's picking up.
抱歉打扰了 我看你的百叶窗还开着
Sorry to bother you. I saw your shutters open.
进来吧
Come in.
抱歉 我打扰你了吗
Sorry if I'm disturbing you...
没有 没事的
You're not.
暴风雨来时 你的百叶窗不关的话
With your shutters open and a storm brewing,
窗户会碎掉的
your windows'll shatter.
那可真不是时候
That would be bad timing.
这风可能会造成严重的伤害
The wind can do serious damage.
我知道
I know.
九九年你不在这儿 世界末日啊
You weren't here in '99. The end of the world.
我相信 你需要帮忙吗
I believe it. You need a hand?
可能需要 谢谢
Perhaps, yes. Thanks.
我没数过 但是这房子应该
I never counted. but there must be
有二十扇左右窗户
something like 20 windows in this house.
是西风 我们从这里开始就行了
It's a westerly, so let's start there.
在厨房
In the kitchen.
你冷吗
You're cold?
有一点
A little.
去关下一扇窗吧
Next window perhaps?
好
Okay.
我没有想到会有人来
I wasn't expecting anyone.
看上去像野猫战机
Looks like a Grumman Wildcat.
我不知道
I don't know.
我想自己整修一架
I'd love to restore one.
然后飞到纽约
And fly it to New York.
你是飞行员吗
You're a pilot?
不是
No.
人总要有梦想啊
You've got to have a dream.
我们先关那扇吧
Let's start with that one.
抱歉
Sorry.
这个召集的画面得之后再出现
The Summoning scene needs to come later.
- 不 这是  - 库尔特 我们没时间争论
- No. this is...  - Kurt, we have no time to argue.
游戏玩家遇到基拉时
The player encounters Kira
她是甜美的学校老师
in her sweet, schoolteacher persona
还没有重生为邪恶
before her Dark Rebirth.
- 不然就没时间犯错  - 对
- Or there's no boner moment!  - Right.
- 米歇尔  - 什么事
- Michèle.  - Yes?
你有时间吗
Got a minute?
有
Yeah.
我在库尔特私人服务器找到一些东西
I found something on Kurt's private server.
他似乎喜欢碾压
It looks like he's into crushing.
什么是碾压
What's "crushing''?
就是字面意思 碾压
What it sounds like. Crush-sh.
好好享受
Enjoy.
变态 但还不是确切的证据
Twisted, but hardly a smoking gun.
我也这么觉得
I guess not.
很好 继续加油
Good work. Keep on it.
尘土女孩
Ash girl.
Deliciously nasty.
下流美味
你在这儿
You're here?
你疯了吗
You're mad?
我只是好奇
I'm mostly curious.
我想我该解释一下
I guess I should explain.
我本来不会给别人看的
I was never going to show it to anyone.
菲利普·关把它从我的电脑上弄下来
Philippe Kwan ripped it off my computer
然后发了出去
and sent it out.
但这是你做的
But you created it?
是的
Yes.
为什么
Why?
起初是真实的犯罪照片
At first, as a game idea
激发的游戏创意
based on true crime photos.
之后就变得奇怪了
Then it got weird.
如果不是关那个浑蛋发送出去
Nobody would've seen it
没人会知道
if that asshole Kwan hadn't...
如果我被开除了 他也该受罚
If I'm fired, he deserves it too.
把你的老二掏出来
Take out your dick.
什么
Pardon me?
把你的老二掏出来 可能我就不开除你
Show me your dick and I might not fire you.
我那一万还给我吗
It's pretty.
没门
Manon.
你看上去做了割礼
You look circumcised.
我不用还那一万了吗
I still get the 10 grand?
一个也不能少
That's a no.
把那些全删了
And delete all that.
太好了
Fantastic!
滚出去
Get out!
出去
Get out of here!
滚出去
Get out!
西班牙热情洋溢
A wave of enthusiasm in Spain.
教皇方济各将会加入虔诚的朝圣者
Pope Francis will join crowds of pilgrims walking barefoot
光脚走向圣地亚哥·德·孔波斯特拉
on the road to Santiago de Compostela.
在法国
In France,
不出意料 乔治·勒布朗留在监狱
Georges Leblanc stays in prison, unsurprisingly.
这个连环杀手最后一次
The serial killer failed
申请假释失败了
in his latest application for parole.
乔治·勒布朗现年七十六岁
Georges Leblanc is 76 years old.
下一次申请他要再等上十年
He must wait ten years to apply again.
他的律师表示
His lawyers announced he...
去死 去死
Fuck you, fuck you!
我是米歇尔·勒布朗 我昨天打过电话
I'm Michèle Leblanc. I called yesterday.
是的
Right.
在这里等着 有人会接你
Wait there for someone to come get you.
谢谢
Thank you.
勒布朗女士 是吗
Ms. Leblanc?
- 我是监狱长助理  - 你好
- I'm the Assistant Warden.  - Hi.
- 来杯咖啡吗  - 不了 谢谢
- A coffee or something?  - No, thanks.
如果不介意 到我办公室聊吧 这边
Can we talk in my office if you don't mind? This way...
我是来朝我爸脸上吐口水的
I'm here to spit in my father's face.
我不保证我不会这么做
I can't guarantee it's a metaphor.
人们来这儿 有各种原因
People have all kinds of reasons.
我来是因为那个浑蛋影响我太多了
I came because I gave the bastard too much power over me.
我的一生都在逃离他 惧怕他
My whole life fleeing him, fearing him.
真是浪费
What a waste!
勒布朗女士
Ms. Leblanc...
你父亲去世了
Your father is dead.
早晨快到八点时
Shortly before 8 am,
我们发现他死在了牢房里
we found him deceased in his cell.
怎么会
How?
接下来会有调查
There'll be an investigation,
他似乎是用床单上吊自杀的
but he appears to have hanged himself with a sheet.
什么时候的事情
When did this happen?
我们认为在晚了点到早了点之间
We only know it must have been between 7pm and 7am.
几点通知我父亲我今天会来的
At what time was my father notified that I was coming today?
快到晚上七点时
Shortly before 7pm.
你的母亲要求过火化尸体
Your mother requested cremation,
把他俩的骨灰放在一起
with a vault for his ashes next to hers.
即使她的牌位在他旁边 她也不会在那儿
She won't be there, even if her plaque's next to his.
我有很多事情要和他说
I had a list of things to say to him.
九个要点
Nine bullet points.
因为我来 你就死了
I killed you by coming here.
你好
Hello?
我是《巴黎人报》记者 艾米丽·方丹
Emilie Fontaine, reporter at Le Parisien.
我想问问您对父亲的去世怎么看
I was wondering if you'd like to comment on your father's passing.
你是怎么弄到我的电话号码的
How did you get this number?
我知道这时间有点尴尬
I realize it's an awkward time.
这对你来说也是个机会
It's an opportunity for you...
喂
Hello?
勒布朗女士
Ms. Leblanc?
你愤怒吗
Are you feeling anger?
悲伤吗
Grief?
或者觉得解脱吗
Relief perhaps?
安娜的语音信箱 我不能接你电话
Anna's voicemail. I can't take your...
我是理查德 请留言
This is Richard. Leave me a message.
你感觉如何
How are you feeling?
我感觉如何
How am I feeling?
有没有感觉头晕目眩
Are you dizzy? Head spinning?
- 不 我感觉还好  - 好
- No. I'm fine, I think.  - Ok.
除了 我的腿
Except my leg.
别费劲了 卡住了
Don't bother. It's jammed.
打开安全带 我帮你出去
Unbuckle and I'll help you out.
你让我看看怎么样了
You should let me look at it.
我以前踢足球
I played soccer.
很好 那又怎样呢
Great, so what?
我是说我懂一些腿伤的知识
I mean, I know a bit about leg injuries.
我小时候 前交叉韧带撕裂
As a teen, I tore my anterior cruciate ligament.
可以吗
Okay?
用了一年时间恢复
One year of rehab.
好的 我先来消消毒
Alright, I'd better disinfect it now.
扭伤很恼人
A nasty sprain.
它需要治疗
It needs treatment.
那么 感觉怎么样
So, how was it?
爽吗 感觉好吗
Was it good? How was it?
回答我 你享受吗
Answer me. Did you enjoy it?
你为什么要那么做
Why did you do it?
我必须那么做
It was necessary.
- 祝您今天愉快  - 谢谢 再见
- Have a good day, ma'am.  - Thanks. goodbye.
米歇尔 住手 你不能这么做
Stop it, Michèle. You can't do this.
不能做什么
What can't I do?
不敲门就进来
Walking in without ringing the bell.
拉尔夫 我有钥匙 还敲什么门
I have a key, Ralf. Why ring the bell?
别管我 我一会就好
Ignore me, I won't be long.
这和多久没关系
It's not about how long.
- 别惹人讨厌  - 你得马上离开
- Don't be unpleasant.  - You have to go immediately.
这是我的公寓
I own this apartment!
是的 我会离开的
Yes, well I will be going...
等一下 等一下
This is not the time.
反正我卖了 所以我来这里
Anyway I put on sale, that's why I'm here.
我看到你父亲去世了
I saw your father passed away.
世上少了一个浑蛋
One less bastard in the world.
你应该开始收拾你的行李
You should start packing your bags.
我看了电视上你和你爸的节目
I saw all the shows on TV about you and your dad.
你们谋杀那些人的时候
When you murdered all those people.
我看到了所有的尸体 孩子的死尸
I saw all the corpses, all the dead children.
那浑蛋死了 不过至少我和他老婆睡了
The bastard's dead now, and at least I fucked his wife.
喂
Hello?
是罗伯特
It's Robert.
安娜要去伦敦开会 我下午有时间
Anna's gone to her London meeting. My afternoon's free.
罗伯特
Robert.
我本要打电话
I was going to call.
我扭伤了膝盖 还上了支架
I sprained my knee. It's in a brace.
我都快不能走路了
I can hardly walk.
所以 我们不能去滑雪了吗
So? We're not going skiing.
你很棒
You were fabulous.
你怎么想到要装死的
Where'd you get the idea of playing dead?
反正 你得到了你想要的
Anyway. you got what you wanted.
看 我多么讲义气
See, I'm as good as my word.
既然这样
Now that...
这种感觉很奇特
It was a very peculiar sensation.
那我们还可以继续当朋友
So we can still be friends.
你知道我说的朋友指什么
You know what I mean by "friends''?
不再一起睡
No more fucking.
文森特
Vincent
你怎么来了
What are you doing here?
乔西把我赶出来了
Josie kicked me out.
发生什么了
What happened?
我不知道
I don't know.
想一想
So think about it.
无理取闹 肯定有原因
There must be a reason, however demented.
有原因
There's a reason.
我被炒鱿鱼了
I lost my job.
被炒了
Lost?
我辞职了
I resigned.
- 你辞职了  - 我必须辞职
- You resigned?  - l had to.
我的车坏了
My car broke down.
你因为车坏了 所以辞职了
You resigned because your car broke down?
上下班来回各要一个小时
It's one hour there, one hour back, from the house.
那很不健康
That's unhealthy.
我在电视上看到地铁里的空气质量
I saw a thing on TV about air quality in the subway.
你把他带来的吗
You brought him here?
- 我别无选择  - 别无选择
- l had no choice.  - No choice?
乔西威胁我说要去美国
Josie threatened to go to America.
还要带着卢西恩
And take Lucien along.
我不敢相信我居然向着她说话
I can't believe I'm defending her
但她有权利和你生气
but she has a right to be mad at you.
你有责任 要租房子 居然还辞职
You have responsibilities, an apartment, and you quit your job?
她也是这么说的
You say it exactly like her.
我的车坏了 又不是我的错
My car broke down. That's not my fault!
你现在必须把宝宝送回去
You have to give that baby back right now.
你们没结婚 别人可能认为你绑架孩子
You're not married. It could be seen as kidnapping.
绑架 他是我的儿子
Kidnapping? He's my son!
我的儿子
My son!
好吧 他是你儿子
Alright, he's your son.
不 不好
No, not alright.
会是谁呢
Who could that be?
他在哪儿
Where is he?
- 谁  - 我的宝宝
- Who?  - My baby!
- 他在哪儿  - 楼上
- Where is he?  - Upstairs.
我的宝宝 你把他怎么了
My baby! What did you do to him?
我把他怎么样了
What did I do to him?
我连仓鼠都不敢托付给你
I wouldn't trust you with a hamster!
放开我 放开我
Let go! Let go of me!
放开她
Let go of her.
放开我 该死
Let go of me, dammit!
放开她
Let go of her!
放开我
Let go of me!
文森特
Vincent!
什么
What?
这是我的孩子 明白吗
He's my baby, get it?
我的孩子
My child!
对你来说 一直都是为了孩子
It was always about the baby for you.
你都是为了他
You were in it for his sake.
我可以做个好父亲
I could be a good father.
我知道
I know it.
这个
These?
可以 不加盐的
Sure, but unsalted ones.
嗨 文森特
Hi, Vincent.
- 好吗  - 你呢
- Okay?  - And you?
买邦尼维牌的 是在弗洛朗热做的
Buy Bonne Vie. They're made in Florange.
晚上好 米歇尔
Evening, Michèle.
你的膝盖怎么样了
How's your knee?
你呢 你的手怎么样了
And you? Your hand?
帕特里克说邦尼维不加盐薯片
Patrick said Bonne Vie unsalted chips
是在弗洛朗热制作的
are made in Florange.
瑞贝卡去旅行了 给我留了很多意面
Rebecca's on a trip and left tons of lasagna.
我肯定吃不完
I'll never be able to finish it.
我买了这个搭配着面吃
I got this to go with it.
听着不错
Sounds good to me.
是啊
Yes. sure.
谢谢 不用了
No, thanks.
瑞贝卡和父母去哪里旅行了
Where did Rebecca and her parents go?
去圣地亚哥德孔波斯特拉见教皇
To see the Pope in Santiago de Compostela.
开车 最后要步行
Driving and on foot at the end.
我听说他会在大教堂里做弥撒
I saw he'll be saying mass in the cathedral.
教皇
The Pope.
我想不到他光着脚的样子
I have a hard time imagining the guy barefoot.
很难想象他是个真人 还有脚
It's so weird to think he's a real person, like with feet.
少喝点 亲爱的
Go easy, sweetheart.
他睡着了
He's out.
眼睛大 肚子小
Eyes bigger than his belly.
谢谢你
Thank you.
地板很温暖
The floor's warm.
我自己安装了地暖
It's a wood boiler. I installed it myself.
听着还挺难的
Sounds like a job.
对
Yes.
火焰燃烧转换器
Works by inverted flame combustion.
Inverted flame combustion?
- 感觉好像你自己编的词  - 不
- Sounds like you just made it up.  - No.
我没自己编
I'm not making anything up.
就在地下室里
It's in the basement.
我能想象到
I can imagine.
想去看看吗
You want to see it?
好
Ok.
就是这儿了
There we are.
关上门 什么噪音也听不到
All noise is muffled by the door.
- 文森特在楼上  - 是的
- Vincent's upstairs.  - Yes, he is.
来吧
Do it.
这样不信
It doesn't work like that.
反正对我来说不行
Not for me.
得要像之前一样
It has to be like before.
我们走
Let's go.
谢谢你的招待
Thank you for dinner.
客气了
Anytime.
库尔特
Kurt.
干得好
Bravo.
安娜 我有个主意
Anna, I have an idea.
游戏发布会的聚会
The party for the game launch.
我们可以让文森特来组织
we could ask Vincent to organize it.
好主意
Good idea.
我知道我一直不愿意给文森特工作
I know I was always against throwing work Vincent's way but...
怎么了
What's wrong?
罗伯特和其他人上床了
Robert's fucking someone.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我认得那味道
I recognized the scent
是他们在旅店用的破沐浴液
of that stupid body wash they use in hotels
还想显得高档
trying to be classy.
我们家不用那样的
We don't have that at home.
那是你唯一的证据吗
That's your only evidence?
我闻了他的内衣
I smelled his underwear.
我等了一夭等他把内裤脱下来
I waited all day for him to take off his shorts.
他最后脱下来后 我扑上去闻了闻
When he did at last, I pounced on them. And sniffed.
我感到无比羞愧
I felt ashamed beyond words.
羞愧可不足以阻挡咱们做事
Shame isn't a strong enough emotion to stop us doing anything at all.
相信我
Believe me.
你要变成常客了
You're becoming a regular.
好像是
Looks like it.
- 你的妻子呢  - 她来不了
- Your wife?  - Couldn't make it.
你啊是什么意思
What do you mean, "Ah''?
我们应该一起来的 拼车现在正流行
We should've come together. Carpooling is hip.
你好吗
How are you?
馥颂给咱们做的 尝尝 很好吃
Fauchon made this up for us. Taste that. it's awesome.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hi.  - Hi.
这边
Right this way.
今晚你主持的吗
You're maitre d' tonight?
妈妈让我来负责这个聚会
Mom put me in charge of the party.
晚上好
Evening.
- 你好吗  - 很好
- How are you?  - Fine.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Good evening.  - Good evening.
- 你好吗  - 挺好的
- How are you?  - Good.
抱歉 口红弄到你脸上了
Sorry, lipstick on your cheek.
欢迎来到我家
Welcome to my home.
想试试吗
Want to give it a try?
不了 我不喜欢玩游戏
No, thanks, I'm no gamer.
真的吗
Really?
- 我想试试 你教教我  - 好
- I'd love a go. Show me?  - Ok.
- 晚上好  - 晚上好
- Good evening.  - Good evening.
你想喝点什么
Can I get you a drink?
- 香槟吗  - 红酒吧 谢谢
- Champagne?  - Red wine, please.
我也喝红酒吧
I'll switch to red, too.
- 你也要香槟吗  - 不了 谢谢
- Champagne for you?  - No, I'm good.
一瓶红酒 谢谢
Bottle of red, please.
我的工作是把酒倒在杯子里
I was told to pour glasses.
这里我说了算
I'm in charge here.
给我的指令很明确
I was given specific instructions.
威士忌 谢谢
Whiskey here, please.
快点 再快点
Faster, much faster!
你可以按这个圆形
You can press the circle.
现在让他走
Get him moving now.
按这里是跳
Press there to jump.
你怎么没带海琳一起
You didn't bring Hélène?
我们见过了
We've met now.
实话实说 我们结束了
I won't lie to you. It's over.
发生什么了
What happened?
躺在床上 我问她最喜欢我的哪本书
Laying in bed, I asked her which of my books was her favorite.
你问这个干吗
Why'd you do that?
她说《白杨香气》
She said Scent of Poplar.
《白杨香气》
Scent of Poplar
那是皮埃尔·卡沙的小说
is a novel by one Pierre Casamayou.
我都不知道有两个卡沙
I'd no idea there were two Casamayous.
很显然 他很有才华
Apparently, he's talented.
可怜的理查德
Poor Richard.
是的 可怜的理查德
Yes, poor Richard.
所以
So...
我们尽了最大的努力
it looks like somehow, despite our best efforts,
现在终于成功了
we have a success on our hands.
我唯一能说的就是谢谢
All I can say is thank you.
敬祝身体健康 开开心心
to your good health and hip hip hooray!
米歇尔 米歇尔 米歇尔
Michèle! Michèle! Michèle!
米歇尔 米歇尔
Michèle! Michèle!
好的
Well...
我没有更好的言语来表达了
I couldn't put it any better.
玩得开心
Have a great evening!
你见过理查德吗
Have you met Richard?
之前理查德提过一个非常有趣的提议
Some time ago, Richard pitched a very interesting idea.
你们两个携手 肯定会非常厉害
You two working together could make something fabulous of it.
至少我这么认为
I think, at least.
你们一起聊聊吧
Talk it over.
这不是施舍吗
This isn't charity?
你该了解我的
You should know me better than that.
告诉他你的想法
Go on, tell him your idea.
我把它设计在
So, it's set in a...
我来给你拿杯喝的
Let me get you a drink.
我们随时可以走 亲爱的
We can go whenever you want, darling.
我们在床上肯定比在这里有趣
We'll have more fun in bed than here.
伙计们 想来点威士忌吗
How about a whiskey, guys?
给我一分钟 然后我们就走
Give me a minute, then we can go.
随你
Whatever you say.
两杯威士忌 一杯橙汁 谢谢
Two whiskeys and an OJ, please.
太棒了
It's going great!
是我
It's me.
什么是你
What's you?
和罗伯特上床的是我
It's me, sleeping with Robert.
现在都结束了 但那时是我
It's over now, but it was me.
多久了
How long?
六到八个月
6-8 months.
我一点都不知道
I didn't have a clue.
我知道
I know.
你做什么了
What did you do?
我坦白了
I stopped lying.
- 再见  - 再见
- See you.  - See you.
拿着我的钥匙 帕特里克开车送我回去
Take my keys. Patrick's driving me home.
- 你这就要走了  - 你做得非常好
- You're leaving already?  - You did wonderfully.
放松
Relax.
再见
See you.
变态
It's twisted.
- 什么  - 变态
- Sorry?  - Twisted.
我们之间是病态的
Between us, it's sick. Diseased.
我之前不承认 但我现在清楚了
I was in some kind of weird denial but I see clearly now.
你清楚什么了
What do you see?
你对我做的事情 你以为你逃得掉
You don't expect to get away with what you did to me?
我马上会做我早该做的事
I'll do what I should've done at once.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
不仅仅是关于我 还有你的老婆
It's not just about me. There's your wife, too.
可能还有其他人
And others, perhaps.
谁知道呢
Who knows.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你还对多少其他人做过同样的事情
How many others? That you've done the same thing to?
我要去报警 告诉他们一切
I'll go to the police. I'll tell them everything.
为什么
Why?
都结束了
It's over.
勒布朗女士
Ms. Leblanc?
- 你好  - 你好
- Hello.  - Hello.
你和死者之间是什么关系
What was your relationship with the deceased?
他是我的邻居
He was my neighbor.
只是一起喝咖啡的邻居吗
Like have-a-cup-of-coffee neighbor?
还是互相借除草机的邻居
Borrow-the-lawnmower neighbor?
不 我从没借过他的除草机
No, I never borrowed his lawnmower.
但是
But it was...
对 是那种邻居
Yes, that kind of neighbor.
直到
Until maybe...
最近
recently.
他和你一起参加这个聚会的时候吗
When he attended this party with you?
是的
Yes.
那时你们关系变得
That's when your relationship became
更加私人了吗
more personal?
对 我的意思是
Yes. I mean...
是朝那个方向发展
It was heading in that direction.
当这个男人带着面具出现在你屋子里
When this man appeared in your house, masked,
你没怀疑过他可能是你的邻居吗
you never suspected for a moment it might be your neighbor?
谁会想到呢
Who could imagine such a thing?
- 颜色可以吗  - 刚刚好
- The color okay for you?  - Just fine.
非常好
It's perfect.
小心 这些雕塑很易碎
Careful, the statues are fragile.
瑞贝卡
Rebecca!
你好
Hi.
你找到买家了吗
You found a buyer?
我损失了一点 但还可以
I took a bit of a hit, but not too bad.
房地产经纪人很厉害
The realtor did a great job.
如果你需要 我把他联系方式给你
I'll give you his details. If ever you...
我哪里也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
东西都堆起来
Stuff piles up.
我想告诉你
I wanted you to know...
我
I'm ...
你经历这些 我很难过
I'm very sorry for all you've been through.
幸运的是 我有信念
Fortunately, I have faith.
信念就是帮人度过艰难时期用的
What's it for if not to get through tough times?
帕特里克是个好人 但他的灵魂受了折磨
Patrick was a good man but he had a tortured soul.
- 再见  - 再见
- Goodbye.  - Goodbye.
米歇尔
Michèle!
我很高兴你能给他他所需要的
I'm sincerely glad you could give him what he needed.
至少给过
For a time, at least.
嗨
Hey there!
好漂亮
Wow, beautiful!
过来看看
Check it out.
乔西让我选的
Josie let me choose.
敞篷车
A convertible.
他自己赚的
He's earned it.
你好
Hello.
我们走吧
Let's go.
宝宝
Baby!
开心吗
Happy?
疯了 艾琳勒布朗 乔治勒布朗
Crazy!
我听说你在这里
I heard you were here.
我人是在这里了
Physically, anyway.
我们要开展理查德的项目了
We're going ahead with Richard's project?
让他胡闹一段时间吧
Let him fool around for a while.
罗伯特怎么样
How's Robert?
- 我把他赶出去了  - 不是吧
- I kicked him out.  - No.
从那之后他就触底了
Ever since, he's hit the bottle.
你看上他什么了
What did you see in him?
就是那么一样
It was just one of those things.
一个机会
An opportunity.
我想和人睡觉
I wanted to get laid.
没别的 就是很不堪
That's no excuse. It was shabby.
比那还糟糕
Worse than that even.
文森特长大了呢
Vincent's grown up now.
就我们两个人
It's just the two of us.
大房子里就我一个人
And I'm all alone in that huge house.
我准备卖了它
I'm going to sell it.
我想我可以搬来和你一起住段时间
I was thinking I could move in with you for a while.
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者